# **Brent Phillips**

Brentophillips@outlook.com | 1.415.481.7156 | LinkedIn.com/in/brentophillips

### Summary

I manage tech focused community organizations around the world and AI for Good projects in my spare time while working for an explainable AI research laboratory and a healthcare diagnostics company during the day. I'm also currently pursuing a Master's degree in Computer Science and heading the launch of a Partnership on Generative AI for Humanitarian Applications linking humanitarian organizations, academic institutions and tech companies.

Expertise: I excel in program and project management, strategic partnerships building, podcast production, quality control, operating and maintaining robotic equipment and in managing manufacturing and shipping operations. I'm passionate about humanitarian applications of artificial intelligence, open data sharing frameworks and in research around uses of AI in healthcare and manufacturing. I also possess considerable experience in humanitarian relief operations, logistics, mechanical maintenance, industrial operations and in mentoring startups and hackathon participants.

#### Skills

Program and Project Management, Partnership Building, Community Management, Event Organization, Marketing, Robotic Operations, Mechanical Maintenance, Quality Control Inspection, Non-destructive Testing, Laboratory Technology, Warehousing, Regulatory Compliance, Shipping, Humanitarian Relief Operations, Logistics. Languages: French, basic Spanish, basic Portuguese, basic German

#### Education

Master's degree, **Computer Science** (present studies) Roux Institute, Northeastern University, Portland, Maine

Master's degree, **Humanitarian Operations** University of Geneva, Switzerland

Bachelor's degree, **Architecture** (unfinished)

California Polytechnic State University, San Luis Obispo, California

#### Experience

**Research Assistant**, University of Pittsburgh Health and Explainable Al Lab, 2023 - Present Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania

• Launched and produce the lab's Health and Explainable AI podcast series, source quests, interface with students and develop strategic partnerships

**Organizer**, Princeton School of Al Meetup Group, 2022 - Present Portland, Maine (volunteer)

Organize discussions and AI for Good projects for Princeton University students

Club Lead, Google Developer Student Clubs, 2021 - 2022

Portland, Maine (volunteer)

 Launched and managed a Google Developer Student Club at Northeastern University's Roux Institute, organized peer-to-peer learning initiatives, discussions and volunteer projects for students

Robot Machine Operator, Abbott Laboratories, 2020 - Present

Portland, Maine

• Manufacture health diagnostic test kits, operate industrial robots, train staff

Instrument Technician, IDEXX, 2018 - 2020

Portland, Maine

Repaired, calibrated and tested chemistry analyzers for a pet healthcare company

Community Manager and Project Manager, Humanitarian Al, 2018 - Present

Cambridge, Massachusetts (volunteer)

 Manage the Humanitarian AI meetup community linking meetup groups in fifteen cities around the world, produce the Humanitarian AI Today podcast series, manage volunteer projects focusing on tackling ways AI applications can answer complex queries posed by humanitarian actors

Innovation Manager, OneRelief, 2018 - 2019

Cambridge, Massachusetts (part-time)

Managed an innovation lab at a humanitarian crowdfunding startup

## Office Services Associate, Fitbit, San Francisco, 2017 - 2018

Maintained office and IT systems

Warehouse Associate, Amazon, 2016 - 2017

San Francisco, California

Warehoused products, dispatched drivers

Startup Founder, Beehive, 2012 - 2018

San Francisco, California (volunteer)

• Co-founded and worked on building a humanitarian crowdfunding startup

Database Editor and Language Translator, FedEx Trade Networks, 2006 - 2018

San Francisco, California

 Researched, translated and databased world customs documentation, managed and edited a customs database, reviewed localization outputs

Administrative Assistant, United Nations, 2005 - 2006

Geneva, Switzerland

 Administered UNOSAT's Earth Observation User Liaison Office, managed partnerships, organized events, evaluated satellite imagery

Telecommunications Technician, AT&T, 1997 - 2001

San Francisco, California

Repaired and installed telecommunications circuits

Humanitarian Relief Worker, SAGE International Europe, 1993 - 2000

Paris, France (volunteer)

 Organized humanitarian relief operations in Bosnia-Herzegovina and Albania, escorted aid convoys and setup aid distributions networks

QC Inspector and Plant Operator, Pacific Gas and Electric Company, 1987 - 2001

San Luis Obispo, California

 Inspected, operated and maintained mechanical power plant systems, carried out non-destructive testing and chemical analysis, warehoused equipment and consumables, trained staff